<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Researches | Academic</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/</link><atom:link href="https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Researches</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://boyinfeng.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Researches</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/</link></image><item><title>Where do moral inclinations come from?</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/psyc-0283/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/psyc-0283/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This was the essay for UCL course &lt;strong>PSYC0283 Moral Cognition&lt;/strong> directed by &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=cdPofb0AAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;oi=ao" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr Dorottya Lantos&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=lcVeH58AAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;oi=ao" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr Jess Rea&lt;/a> in 2022. It comprises a 500-word blog post for the lay audience, and a 1500-word academic essay which both address the same question. Distinction achieved (80/100).&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moral principles guide human behaviours by determining right from wrong. Two major moral principles exist - deontology, which focuses on the consistency of actions with social norms, and utilitarianism, which focuses on the overall consequences of actions. These principles reflect how individuals approach moral dilemmas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Early theories emphasised reasoning in developing morality, proposing that moral understanding progresses through cognitive stages as children mature. However, contemporary research highlights moral intuitions, suggesting judgments stem from automatic emotional evaluations beyond consciousness. Dual-system frameworks now integrate affective and cognitive contributions to moral judgments. Affective intuitions typically align with deontology, while controlled reasoning reflects utilitarianism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To examine the origins of moral inclinations, it is necessary to differentiate between intuitive and abstract moral reasoning. This paper reviews evidence from developmental psychology and neuroscience to argue that both biological and social origins shape moral inclinations. Specifically, humans are predisposed to moral intuitions but accumulate cognitive resources for moral reasoning as they mature. Importantly, moral inclinations can vary greatly between dilemmas with similar settings due to differing emotional engagement, and reported moral intentions in hypothetical scenarios may not reflect realistic decisions or behaviours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do individual differences in face and emotion recognition abilities emerge during development?</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/psyc-0164/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/psyc-0164/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This was the 3000-word essay for UCL course &lt;strong>PSYC0164 Social Neuroscience&lt;/strong> directed by &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=vNqtGKcAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;oi=ao" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof Antonia Hamilton&lt;/a> in 2022. Distinction achieved (82/100).&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Research on typical and atypical development provides insight into the origins of individual differences in face and emotion recognition abilities. Findings indicate that both genetic and environmental factors contribute to variability through complex interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Typical development studies show that while basic recognition abilities emerge early, configural and holistic processing take time to develop. Skills improve dramatically from childhood to adulthood, highlighting the role of experience. Preferential exposure leads to own-race biases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Atypical development reveals potential genetic bases. Individuals with autism or prosopagnosia have face processing deficits linked to genetic mutations and neural abnormalities. Dissociations between skills in syndromes like Williams syndrome demonstrate distinct processing routes. Heritability studies estimate high genetic influence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, genes likely determine basic neural architecture and individual potential. However, environmental stimulation is essential for shaping connections and skill progression. Further research using longitudinal and neuroimaging approaches is needed to elucidate precise mechanisms within this gene-environment interplay.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do affective and motivational states influence the stability of political ideology?</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/psyc-0162/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boyinfeng.github.io/research/psyc-0162/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This was the 3000-word essay for UCL course &lt;strong>PSYC0162 Social Cognition, Affect and Motivation&lt;/strong> directed by &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=tbk3KoIAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;oi=ao" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof Ana Guinote&lt;/a> in 2021. Distinction achieved (76/100).&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past few decades, research on political ideology has focused heavily on personality traits and genetics. However, this risks portraying ideology as predetermined and stable throughout life. As polarization worldwide continues to increase domestic conflicts and global insecurity, the alterable aspects of ideological formation warrant more attention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building on prior work, this study conceptualizes political ideology as having cognitive, affective, and motivational properties. Compared to the more rational cognitive processes, the affective and motivational components involve arousal and sensitivity to contextual stimuli. As such, this study examines how two closely related stimuli-sensitive states - affect and motivation - can influence political ideology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Affect refers to a broad range of valenced feeling states including emotions and moods. Motivation denotes the processes underlying effort toward goals. The central premise is that ideology forms partly through how individuals respond affectively to their environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There appear to be two potential pathways for affective and motivational states to impact ideology. First, affect as a feeling state may directly alter ideological flexibility by changing the scope and focus of information processing. Second, specific emotions and moods could stimulate motivations that either reinforce or reshape one&amp;rsquo;s ideology based on epistemic and existential needs.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>