<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Academic</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://boyinfeng.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>Evaluating Reconstruction Accuracy in Neural Decoding Models</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/neuromatch2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/neuromatch2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Decoding models may use human fMRI responses to an image for reconstructing the original image. That is - &amp;ldquo;we see what we think&amp;rdquo;. For the project at Neuromatch Academy 2022, we are interested in whether human judgment or metrics for quantifying model performance on image reconstruction reflect more preciseness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Human participants (N = 6, 3F, 3M; Age range: 23-27) were asked to a) match two sets (colored and grayscale) of reconstrcuted images to their original versions, and rate the perceived similarity on a scale of 0-100%, whereas algorithmic judgment was evaluated via RMSE (Root Mean Squared Error) and FSIM (Feature Similarity Index)
in Python using the image_similarity_metrics package (Müller et al., 2020).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Findings:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In general, females matched the reconstructed images with the original ones more accurately and more quickly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Males perform better with grayscale images&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mean similarity ratings were lower for males than females&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Human judgment of both genders outperforms the two metrics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FSIM outperforms RMSE&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Neural correlates of visual emotional word processing - An fMRI study</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/fmri2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/fmri2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This was the course project for &lt;strong>PSYC 0073 - Designing and Analysing fMRI experiments&lt;/strong> supervised by &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=kCgH6AgAAAAJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof Joseph Devlin&lt;/a>. 78/100 Distinction achieved.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In general, the activations observed in the current study are consistent with previous findings, especially in semantic processing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Across three contrasts, OFC activation was identified, suggesting that this area was commonly involved in the current lexical task, and its degree of activation depended on the types of stimuli. Left inferior and middle gyrus, bilateral temporal and parietal lobes showed greater activity in response to real words than to pseudowords.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, activation of most areas involved in affective processing was not detected as predicted, which raises questions about our manipulation of word emotionality. Another explanation might be that the valence effects of positive words are generally more pronounced than those of negative words (e.g., Kuchinke et al., 2005). As we used negative words to represent emotional words in the study, the emotion effects were less obvious, or even non-existent. If future studies with exclusively positive words demonstrate significant emotion effects in brain activation, we might be able to deduce an asymmetry of sensitivity towards word valence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anti-fan polarisation on Weibo</title><link>https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/anti-fan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://boyinfeng.github.io/project/anti-fan/</guid><description>&lt;p>The study examines the highly influential group of &amp;ldquo;anti-fans&amp;rdquo; (extreme haters) of Chinese actor Xiao Zhan on Chinese social media &lt;em>Weibo&lt;/em>. Using sentiment analysis and behavioral coding, 1303 valid Weibo posts from black fans were analyzed to summarize their emotional patterns and behavioral modes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grounded in interaction ritual chain theory, this study explores the underlying reasons behind this group&amp;rsquo;s activities. Preliminary findings indicate the behaviors of black fans can be categorized into direct and indirect types. The anonymous identities and collective identity of the group on social media lower individual moral sensibilities, while their behavioral patterns expand upon those of previous black fan groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This research provides insight into the sentiment and actions of influential anti-fan groups on Chinese social media through quantitative content analysis and established sociological theory.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>